- What if you had a fresh intern
who could remember everything you said
and really understand your customer,
who they are, what they like,
their purchase behavior.
What if they intuitively grasp
the value of a good lead
and who you should target,
all at the speed of light?
You just provide them
with a little guidance
and let them run with it.
Well, that would be an ideal employee.
And that employee is
real and available today
in something called supervised learning.
It's an engine that's powering
the frontier of marketing.
In this video, I want
to help you understand
what supervised learning is.
So you can make real decisions
about how you can use this technology
to help you improve your marketing.
You'll know where it makes sense
and how it can really help.
Supervised learning is
where you teach the machine
through example and correction.
You can't really explain
how you know a cat is a cat,
but you know one when you see one.
Writing a bunch of software rules
to define a cat is beyond difficult.
But if you give the machine
a million pictures of cats,
it can determine how to
recognize a cat on its own,
especially as you correct
it when it's wrong,
that's the supervision part.
Give the machine everything
you know about your customers,
tell it which ones are
your best customers,
and it can figure out what
the best have in common.
You don't need to outline
a persona or a profile.
The machine learns from the data.
Then you can ask the machine
to find non-customers out in the world
that might fit the general profile
of your best customers.
Your list of current customers
is the training data.
The machine looks at your list,
figures out what they have in common,
and decides which elements
are the most predictive of goodness.
Using these criteria,
it looks at prospective customers
and shows you the ones
you should be targeting.
You then get the chance to say,
"Yes, these are the cats I'm looking for,"
or correct the machine by saying,
"These are dogs," or
"This is not a prospect,
this is a competitor,"
or "This is a student,"
and it won't make the same mistake again.
Now a word of warning.
The machine might decide
that all your best customers
are named Daniel, so it brings you
all the Daniels it can find.
While that might be statistically true,
it's not useful.
Carry on a conversation with the machine
until it starts coming up
with good enough answers
then better answers, and then
results that are far superior,
and in much less time than humans can.
The machine learns by example,
and by you guiding it,
and rejecting the answers
that might be true, but aren't helpful.
Now in order to uncover
how machine learning
can make the most
difference in your company,
I want you to make a prioritized list
of which tasks would be best
for supervised learning at the moment.
Your ideas could sound like,
"Did our logo show up
today's social media feed?"
"Did our competitor's logo show up?"
"What do our best blog
posts have in common?"
"Where should we open
our next retail store?"
Now, you list some ideas on your own.
Because at the end of the day,
supervised learning boosts
your cognitive skills,
helps you apply your knowledge at scale,
and lets you produce significant results
to transform your marketing.