- Skynet from the "Terminator" learned
at a geometric rate and became
self-aware in 3 1/2 weeks.
In panic, humans tried to pull the plug.
Skynet fought back.
You are so much smarter
than an artificial intelligence system.
Can AI calculate lightning fast? Yes.
Does it have common sense? No.
Does AI have logic? Indubitably.
Does it reason? It does not.
Does AI possess curiosity? Not a trace.
You're not going to be successful
with artificial intelligence
unless you understand where
it falls down on the job.
Stick with me for a couple of minutes
and you'll understand how
important you the human are
to AI working well in marketing.
Without empathy, common sense,
and emotional understanding,
artificial intelligence is
just blinking lights in clockwork.
You add humanity to the picture,
insight, inspiration, creativity.
So your first job when
dealing with an AI system
is all about the smell test.
When the sophisticated AI model calculates
that you would sell more
snow tires in the summer
because, hey, there's no
competitive promotions,
the smell test is quick
to point out the error.
When your algorithm spits
out an auto response
that the company does not
accept returns after 30 days,
your smell test says, hold on there.
This is one of our favorite customers
or one of our most important clients
or one of the most vocal influencers.
We will happily accept
their return and apologize.
The smell test uses
empathy, people skills,
and sales tactics learned over the years,
skills that only you the human possess.
Your job, your superpower, is to identify
what problem needs to be solved,
invent and adopt new ideas,
detect when the result
doesn't pass the smell test.
The ability to look at
one thing and see another,
the power of analogies, the
quest for new knowledge,
these are the human traits
that you must embrace and develop.
They are what sets us
apart from the computer.
You can strengthen your human talent
with some cognitive exercises.
Spot the relationships between things.
How do things interrelate?
Look at things from a different angle.
What if they were upside
down or ran backwards?
Read up on critical thinking.
Am I keeping an open mind?
Test your assumptions.
What would disprove my belief?
Spend one hour a week
studying cognitive bias
to understand how your own
brain is tripping you up.
AI is amazing, but humans are awesome.
Just ask Shakespeare.
"What a piece of work is man,
how noble in reason,
how infinite in faculty,
in form and moving how
express and admirable,
in action how like an angel,
in apprehension how like a god."