- If you're trying to bring the power
of artificial intelligence
into your business today,
you may have to overcome the naysayers
who don't believe AI is
ready for prime time yet.
To convince the doubters,
you only need to explain
a few of the building
blocks that came together
to make AI a reality.
Artificial intelligence
was dreamed up decades ago.
It flourished for a while in the 1960s,
and then disappeared in
disfavor until the late '90s.
But we go back to 1950 when Alan Turing
published a paper called,
"Computing Machinery and
Intelligence" which was all theory.
If computers could run fast enough
and if there was enough data,
then maybe the math could work like this.
The term artificial
intelligence was coined in 1956
at a conference at Dartmouth College.
Between then and the mid-70s,
venture capital was thrown
at AI where we discovered
that it is much harder than we thought.
But four things came together
around the turn of the century
that made AI possible.
First, Google and Yahoo figured
out how to link together
huge numbers of computers,
central processing units, CPUs,
giving us massive computing power.
And the gaming industry
played a big part here
because they had manufactured
graphical processing units,
GPUs, which were much
faster and just the ticket
for the kind of calculations AI needs.
Next was the explosive
growth of the amount of data
that we have at our fingertips,
megabytes and gigabytes
just wasn't enough.
We would need terabytes
and petabytes of data
for AI to chew one, and now we have it
thanks to the internet.
And the internet also gave
us a giant leap forward
in online data storage, the cloud.
Not only did we have a huge
amount of data to play with,
there was finally a place to store it all.
The last piece of the puzzle
was the whole open source movement.
When software is published openly,
everybody can make improvements,
speeding the process.
Because of open-source philosophy,
the majority of research into
AI has been freely published
for anybody to read and to use.
Google, Microsoft, IBM,
Amazon have all made AI tools
and access to data all but free
in order to encourage the world
to push this technology forward.
Put all these together and
we can now run AI programs
on your phone and your wristwatch.
So next time somebody
tries to block your idea
about putting AI to
use in your department,
you can confidently tell
them that the time has come,
now is the time to get started.