- You've probably been in that meeting
where some senior executive says,
"Let use machine learning!"
like it's the most
brilliant idea of the year.
And you use all of your
self-control not to roll your eyes
and mutter, "Management
by in-flight magazine."
Machine learning may be the
most powerful software ever,
but it's not magic.
It's not good at solving all problems.
So what do you say?
Today, I'm going to help you figure out
when machine learning is overkill
and when it is the right tool for the job.
Remember that machine learning
is really good at correlation.
People with this trait
usually have that trait.
People with kids buy more cereal.
Segmentation, these people
are more alike than others.
They like to log on early in the day.
Clustering, there are 10
distinct groups of people,
and you can message them differently.
And anomalies, these people are standouts.
They don't look like anybody else.
There may be something
wrong with the data,
or there might be a business
opportunity hidden inside.
In other words, machine
learning is good for ranking,
sorting, finding patterns,
finding lookalikes,
and finding that needle in a haystack.
So you're looking for
repetitive high-volume tasks
with lots and lots of clean data,
like social media monitoring.
Which of these tweets should
get a canned response?
Which should get reviewed by a human?
Which should we just ignore?
Or advertising or testing
or personalization,
lead scoring, things like that.
The most important step is figuring out
if any other method can solve the problem
or answer the question.
You don't want to fire up an 18-wheeler
to run down to the corner store.
You don't need a cannon to swat a fly.
Machine learning might
be the coolest thing
to hit the management department,
but it costs a lot more
than using a spreadsheet
or building a statistical model by hand.
Let these key questions be your guide
when considering machine
learning for a given project.
Do you have tens of thousands
or millions of examples?
That would be customers or
transactions or ad placements.
Do you have an overwhelming number
of combinations of elements?
Maybe you have a thousand
variables or traits
about each customer to
sift through and correlate.
Is your data squeaky clean?
If not, the cost just went way up
because you have to clean it first.
Is your data well-labeled?
Context is everything.
Otherwise, it's just noise.
Are you sure simpler methods won't work?
Try Excel first.
Heck, sometimes you could just flip a coin
to make some decisions.
Do you have clear goals?
You need an unmistakable definition
of what success looks like.
What will you do with the answer?
If you could simply Google the answer,
would it have an impact on the business?
Yes? Good.
But what if it cost $50,000
and took six weeks to answer the question?
Is it still worth it?
You bring these questions to the table
next time somebody asks if
they can use machine learning,
and you will instantly be seen
as the most well-informed
marketing professional
on the planet because this list,
it hasn't hit the in-flight magazines yet.
And this exercise sheet
can help you every time.