- Conversation bots have been
struggling to gain respect.
They've been so lame for so long
that the popular meme is what do we want?
Chat bots.
When do we want them?
I'm sorry, I didn't
understand the question.
The chat bots are getting better.
They are learning.
These tools are great for
answering your customers'
frequently asked questions.
You can give your bot
all the right answers.
And then, instead of coming up
with a thousand different
ways people might ask,
the bot learns how people ask
the same question in thousands of ways.
Does it come in brown?
Do you have a brown one?
Can I get it in brown?
How about brown?
Chocolate, coffee, dark tan?
Chatbots are being used
to great effect conversing
with customers, offering
instant customer service,
and actually helping your
customer service teams,
not replacing them.
A travel company found that
people are full of questions.
The same questions again and again
about their flight or their hotel.
Instead of having
employees waste their time
repeating the same answers
to the same questions,
the company implemented chatbots.
By having employees tackle
only the toughest questions,
they increased bookings.
When questions have specific answers,
chatbots are well worth the effort.
Another example is a
popular cosmetics retailer
that built a bot that interviews people
about their makeup
preferences, their skin color,
and a few questions about where they fall
on the conservative to
daring style spectrum.
Then it recommends different products
and colors in the way a sales clerk might.
Then, it uses the customer's camera
to display different lipstick colors
in real time on your face.
The result, more sales.
One office supply company
lets customers order products
with voice or text or even with a photo.
And when you say that you want blue pens,
it's already learned what sort of pens
and how many you usually order.
Time saved, happy customer,
tiny customer service cost.
To prove how advanced
this stuff is getting,
you can now instruct Google
Duplex to make you a reservation
at a restaurant that
has no online booking.
It will call the restaurant on the phone,
talk to the person who answers,
and engage them in conversation.
It understands what's being
said by the human and responds
in real time, including uhs
and ums, to sound more human.
Think about how chatbots
might help take your company
to the next level.
Perhaps you have lots
of customers contacting you all the time.
Maybe you are overwhelmed
with people asking the
same thing over and over.
If you can map out the flow of
a sales clerk's conversation,
then you can choose which
of these ways chatbots
should be put to use first
to help you be more successful at scale.