- "Alice in Wonderland" author
Lewis Carroll reminds us
that if you don't know where
you're going, any road will do.
This is critically important
when dealing with artificial intelligence.
I'm here to make sure your
project doesn't go off the rails
due to a lack of clarity in goal setting.
What happens when you
don't have clear goals?
There's this old story of
an artificial intelligence
tasked to run a paperclip factory
with the goal of optimizing manufacturing.
It streamlines shop floor control,
tightens up the supply chain,
masters the stock market to raise money
to build another factory,
and then it learns hypothetical physics
so it can turn every molecule
on planet Earth into
a paperclip, disaster.
Or say you tune an
algorithm to get more clicks
but it learns to write clickbait,
which makes for a huge amount
of traffic and zero customers.
Not good.
Or you ask your AI system
to optimize for revenue.
So it decides to sell $20
bills for a dollar each,
thereby boosting revenue through the roof
and you're fired.
These are silly examples
of very real problems.
You need to have crystal clear goals
because this is artificial intelligence,
not real intelligence.
A computer only does what you ask it to.
So break the business
problem down into smaller
and smaller problems that
your data team can solve.
The largest problem is
that the CEO says, "We
need bigger profits."
So the head of sales says, "For
that, we need better leads."
And the CMO says, "For that,
"we need better prospect segmentation."
You, the savvy marketing
director, know that for that,
you need to work with the data team
who can make it happen using AI.
You can use supervised learning
to segment your best customers
based on your criteria.
You can use unsupervised learning
to figure out what your best
customers have in common
and look for prospects who most
closely resemble those best customers.
Then you can use reinforcement learning
to test which type of
prospects respond best
to which messaging by micro segment.
But you really need to
get into the weeds here.
You want to test email subject lines?
Great, but first you
need to define success.
What outcome do you want to optimize?
Opens, click-throughs,
conversions, loyalty?
Marketing professionals know
the answer is all of the above.
But the computer does not.
You need to specify one goal
and one goal only very clearly.
I want you to gather your team
and pick a marketing
initiative that is supported
by the highest executive around,
break it down into its component parts,
and pick one and only one task
that is required to accomplish that part,
and then ask yourself this.
Which task would be best
served by an algorithm
that could chew on this
problem day and night at scale?
The data scientist can fly the plane.
The analyst can provide the navigation.
The data is the fuel.
The algorithm is the engine.
But you have to identify the destination.
Having a clear goal in
mind, a clear destination,
is how you get where you're going.