- Years ago, I worked for a company
whose management made
such weird decisions that
about once a week, somebody
on the staff would turn
to the next person,
roll their eyes and say, "Logic
that defies imagination."
It was a frustrating place to work.
Every organization has its
own style, manner, culture,
political traps, but you can survive
and even thrive in bringing
artificial intelligence
into your marketing efforts.
In any environment with
a few key insights.
Start by assessing where your company sits
on the marketing data literacy spectrum.
At one end and are the data
deniers to our old school
mad men types with giant egos
who know that they're smarter
than any data nerd.
If your organization is
at this end of the spectrum, just get out.
Really find another place to work
if you're interested in machine learning.
But what if the firm is data aware,
but not yet data literate?
Then they will likely be receptive
to lunch and learns
carefully crafted webinars
case studies of how other
companies have done well.
Especially if those case studies
are about your competitors.
If your firm falls more
toward the data capable or
data savvy end of the spectrum
lucky you, that means
they are already using
or at least thinking about
using AI in a variety of ways.
And you can show them how
useful it can be in marketing.
Data savvy or just data aware.
If nobody has gotten involved
with AI yet, who has time
then it's up to you to bring
them to the table slowly.
Now's your opportunity
to boost their knowledge
of analytics and statistics.
Explain the whole thing is the difference
between accounting and probability.
Accounting is about facts
expressed with certainty.
Statistics is about likelihood
expressed as degrees of confidence.
How many umbrellas do we
have is much different
than what are the chances
it's going to rain?
When you find those
people who seem to get it
and are interested, it's
time to start some meetups,
casual lunchtime conversations
about the possibilities of using AI.
Form an informal study
group and feed them lunch.
See who has the curiosity
and the time to run some experiments.
This is definitely a skunk works
seeking forgiveness rather
than permission kind of thing.
Just go do it and learn as you do.
This off the record task force
can start collecting stories
and best practices to share with others.
Then it'll be time to search
for a sponsor, some executive level
enthusiast who will support your efforts
throw some budget your way
and help you make progress.
All the while, tell everybody
that your goal is to build
an AI center of excellence.
Everybody wants one of those.