- It's a classic problem, buy or build.
Some people are do it yourselfers
and prefer to fix that
leaky faucet themselves,
to be sure it's done right.
And some, like me, prefer to
have a professional plumber
fix that leaky faucet
because I want to make
sure it's done right.
When it comes to succeeding
with artificial intelligence in marketing,
do you hire a bunch of data scientists
to build an AI system from scratch?
Do you assemble a variety
of AI components and create your own
artificially intelligent
marketing ecosystem?
Or do you license some pre-built platform
that promises to do it all for you?
I want to give you a couple
of things to consider
when answering the question, buy or build.
If you work in a huge corporation,
you likely already have scientists
working on AI for finance,
human resources, manufacturing.
They might have data sciences on board
because their brand,
their image in the marketplace demands it.
Amazon, Google, IBM, Microsoft,
they can't outsource their brain trust.
They want to sell this stuff to others,
so they have to use their own technology.
If you work in a big corporation,
it's likely they already have
teams of people assembled
to master new methods like AI
to increase the company's
overall capabilities.
They might not have tackled marketing yet.
Come up with a pitch for
why they should spend
some time building AI for marketing,
and you'll get their attention.
If you're a small company,
there's no way you can afford
to hire even half a day to scientist.
So just grab the off the shelf system
that solves whatever particular problem
you're facing at the moment.
If your organization is
somewhere in the middle,
you'll need to consider
your corporate culture
and balance the need for instant results
with the need to build internal know-how.
If you have the time,
the political capital,
and the competitive need,
by all means, go out and
hire some data scientists.
Just be sure your budget can handle it,
and that you can afford the time it takes
to find those rare individuals
and get them up to speed.
Now be aware you may
already be using systems
that have AI built in.
IBM has plugged Watson into
all the software they sell.
Adobe has Sensei for
Photoshop and Adobe Analytics.
Salesforce has Einstein.
HubSpot has their content strategy module.
So your first decision
is based on company size.
Giant corporation, do some digging
and find your data science team.
Find out what software your
company is already using.
You'll be surprised how many people
are using different tools
in different departments
and don't know about each other.
And finally, but perhaps most importantly,
ask yourself if you want to do a deep dive
and learn how to build AI systems.
Do you want to bring
together a variety of tools
into your marketing,
computing environment?
You could build your own martech stack,
or do you just want to increase
your return on marketing spend,
make your email campaigns more effective
or boost customer retention?
If so, there are a lot of venture capital
backed tools on the market
you can pick up and run with right away.
Let your personal interest
in artificial intelligence
be your guide and you will
be much more effective
in getting AI to help
you do marketing faster,
cheaper, and at scale.