- Computers are getting really good
at their ability to recognize speech.
No, wait, I didn't say rec a nice beach.
That's where Natural Language Processing
is one of the pillars of
artificial intelligence.
And you can take advantage
of it once you get a feel
for what it is and how it
can be used for marketing.
Natural Language Processing
includes speech recognition,
understanding that this
(clapping) is just noise,
and that these words are speech.
And then transferring that speech to text
so you can dictate texts
or searches in your phone,
and text comprehension,
the art of figuring out
what your words mean.
And finally sentiment analysis,
the art of figuring out how you feel.
Then there's the problem of slang.
If a teenager says that movie
was sick, it's a winner.
But if my 92 year old father says that,
the movie had too much violence in it.
So where is Natural Language
Processing useful in marketing?
It can capture what your customers say
when they talk to you.
You can capture every word over
the phone in the call center
then analyze the call log
for what upsets them the most
or uncover which of your
competitors they ask about.
Wouldn't it be great if you could find out
which product features your customers
complain about the most?
You can.
Natural language
processing is also valuable
for tracking social media.
It can find all the times
people mentioned your company
or product, and based on
positive or negative words,
tell you if people are mostly
happy or getting more unhappy,
same with how they feel
about your competitors.
Natural Language Processing
is speech recognition
that translates speech to
text and then text to meaning.
This is text analysis with smarts.
Natural language processing can analyze
thousands of internal company emails,
marketplace publications,
academic treatises,
and give you specific information
rather than just a list of documents
that might include something
that you're looking for.
By reading all internal emails,
the computer can figure out
who in your organization
gets the most questions
and has the most answers
about a particular topic.
It can reveal the important
passages in newspapers
and journals when you're
researching a new ad campaign
or the competition or marketplace trends.
Natural Language Processing
can compare your blog posts
and your white papers to your competitors
and make recommendations
about how to improve appeal,
readability and Google ranking.
This is search engine
optimization on steroids.
So where would Natural Language Processing
help you the most?
Think about areas in your company
where you have a lot of texts.
Think about places
where it would be useful
to have the computer read and understand
a huge number of pages.
Think about the insights
that you could uncover
if only you had a system
that could read through
all of those reports,
or all of those survey results,
or all of those feedback forms.
Think about keeping tabs on
whether the talk on social media
about you is good or bad.
When you have that list of the ways
that Natural Language Processing can help,
score each one for how
valuable it would be.
At that point, you're ready to investigate
how hard each one would be to accomplish
and how long each one would take.
Do that and you can
easily see which projects
are worth the effort and
which to tackle first.
Alexa, turn off the lights.