- When you understand the power
of artificial intelligence
and machine learning,
and you start putting together
all those capabilities,
you come up with some
pretty remarkable scenarios.
Today, we already have devices
that we can talk to and buy things.
And those devices learn about
you and your ordering habits.
You say, "Send more AA batteries."
Computer has learned what
brand of batteries you prefer,
how many batteries you
usually order and how often.
So it knows what you want and can ask
if you want to subscribe
and receive your usual brand
in usual quantities at set periods
based on your past purchases.
Oh, and by the way,
you can say 5% on the
price by subscribing.
Today, you can point your
phone at products in stores
and have more information
about that product pop up on your screen.
Today, you can walk into a restaurant
and your usual order pops up on the screen
because the algorithm
recognizes your face.
Today, your email system can guess
the rest of the sentence
that you're typing
and you can let it fill in the blank.
But what comes after that?
The savvy marketer isn't
just planning for tomorrow.
They're looking over the horizon
to see what comes the day after tomorrow.
And the day after tomorrow,
marketing gets weird.
Given the difficulties that
we're having with online privacy
and data protection, people are becoming
more concerned about their data.
Imagine a future where
you own your own data
and you store your own data.
And instead of giving your information
to each website and each
company and each app,
you give them access to specific parts
of your personal data.
When you update some piece of information,
every app and website you
have permitted can access it,
and so will never be out of date.
Now, this is your data.
It belongs to you and it's secure.
Now imagine that you have your
own artificial intelligent
agent on top of that data
and it operates on your behalf.
The day will come when your agent says,
"I see that your dishwasher
has a 90% chance of failing
in the next 60 days.
I have found 12 highly rated dishwashers
that will fit in your kitchen,
five of which will fit
in your decorating style.
I have negotiated with four
of them to fit your budget.
And two of them will fit your
schedule for installation."
Between the two, I recommend
the one serviced by a company
five miles from your house,
rather than the 175 miles away.
Would you like the recommended dishwasher
installed next Thursday
or would you like to see more details?"
That's marketing in the future.
That means you have to wrap
your mind around the idea
of machine-to-machine marketing.
You will have to create systems
that can communicate with
your customers' systems
because you might no longer
have direct access to those prospects.
The most important part of your job
will be branding so that your customer
prefers your brand name,
regardless of how far away
your service center is.
So start thinking about it now
and implement what you can,
so you don't fall behind.
It's going to be a wild and
wonderful and exciting time.
And I can't wait to see what we invent,
what you invent tomorrow.