- Artificial Intelligence
is dumb as a rock,
if you don't feed it any data.
Worse than a rock.
You can throw a rock,
build a wall with rocks,
crush them up and make
concrete out of rocks,
but AI without data, useless.
The problem is, which data
should you give an AI system?
This is your problem,
and I can help you with a
couple of important tips
to keep in mind.
The first is the Goldilocks problem.
If you give the computer
too little data to chew on,
it'll make a snap decision
with high confidence that will be wrong.
If you give the computer too much,
it won't be able to
make a decision at all.
Now when I say too little and too much,
I don't mean gigabytes and petabytes,
I mean variety.
You may have heard of the
three V's of big data,
volume, velocity, variety.
Computers are awesome at large quantities
or volume of data.
You have a billion customers?
Not to worry.
You have information
about them coming at you a mile a minute?
Great.
Velocity, no problem.
But variety is what makes or breaks
a machine learning model.
If you only know a few things,
about a billion people
like their name, address and hair color,
the computer isn't going to tell you much.
Maybe there are more
blondes in Sweden than Peru,
but you didn't need machine
learning to figure that out.
If you know 100 variables
about each person,
the system can find
fascinating correlations.
It can determine what marketplaces
are better selling territories,
who is receptive to specific offers,
which behaviors indicate
a propensity to buy.
Now that's useful.
But you can't give the
computer too many variables.
If you give the system
10,000 bits of information
about a billion people,
it's all just noise and the
computer will have no confidence
in anything it finds at all.
The question you have to answer
is which pieces of information
are likely to be the most predictive.
Add a little here, take away there,
until the model that comes
out actually boosts sales.
So how do you know which
data sets are useful?
You don't.
Not yet.
Not at first.
This is a learned skill,
that is particular to your industry,
your company, your customers,
and only you can determine
that not the computer.
What data do you have?
What problem are you trying to solve?
Start by making a list of the data
your company has about your
customers and prospects.
That might be as simple
as looking at your sales
force implementation.
Or it might take months to
ask all the right people.
This inventory or data catalog
is going to be extremely
useful no matter what.
That list is your raw material.
When you review those datasets
and get good at identifying
what might be the most useful
for generating predictive models,
then there will be no stopping you.