- One of my favorite Isaac Asimov quotes
is, the most exciting phrase
that heralds new discoveries
is not eureka, I have found it,
but hmm, that's funny.
Unsupervised learning was invented
to show you what's funny.
Unsupervised learning is where you give
the computer a big pile of data
and ask it to tell you
something you didn't know.
If you have enough data,
then you'll have a clear
enough understanding
of your industry and your customers,
unsupervised learning can unlock doors
in super powerful ways.
Given everything you know
about your customers,
is there a pattern, are there outliers,
what do they have in common?
What sets them apart?
Unsupervised learning doesn't come up
with insightful answers
to a marketing professional's questions,
it just comes up with
interesting correlations,
like more of your
customers are named Susan
than any other name.
People who buy headphones buy more music.
People buy more stuff online
when the weather is bad.
The computer is right, but these things
are obvious, irrelevant and useless,
thank you Captain Obvious.
It might also come up
with other correlations
like the further away from
the store people live,
the more expensive the
items that they buy online.
Or, there's a cluster of online customers
in Toronto who buy your products.
Or, people who open mail number 27
and looked at products A and B
are 50% more likely to add product C
to their shopping cart.
All right, now we're talking.
If people who live further away
from the store buy more
expensive items online,
then we can promote different items
in our direct mail
catalogs, our email blasts,
and ad campaigns based on zip codes closer
to and further away from the store.
We should test that.
There is a cluster of online customers
in Toronto who buy our products.
We have a bunch of
customers, but no store,
we should build one.
People who opened that particular email
and looked at those
products were more likely
to buy product C?
Man, we can boost sales
based on that tomorrow.
You see, inspiration comes from applying
what you know in one area to another.
When unsupervised learning
unearths weird correlations
in the data, your analytics skills kick in
and provide the context, the meaning,
and the implications.
Your computer might tell
you something boring,
people carry umbrellas when it rains.
Or it might tell you
something so compelling
that you might change your
advertising messaging,
identify a new customer base,
or even invent a whole new product line.
So, where do you have
a lot of customer data?
Where might you get more
data about your marketplace?
Gather it together,
give it an unsupervised learning algorithm
and let it show you
something you didn't know.
See, if the results make
you say hmm, that's funny,
then you know you're onto a new discovery.