- We've all seen the movies,
Skynet from "Terminator,"
Sonny from "I, Robot,"
Andrew from "Bicentennial Man,"
Samantha from "Her,"
the list goes on and on.
And it confuses the conversation
about artificial intelligence
to where you need to be very clear
on one critical distinction.
There is general AI, which is
the stuff of science fiction,
and there is functional AI,
which is the stuff of business success
and career advancement.
I want you to fully
understand this difference,
so you'll be on the educated
side of the conversation,
you'll be taken seriously.
You'll be identified as one who gets it.
General artificial intelligence
is the idea that machines will
eventually become self-aware.
The theory is that the
computer learns fast enough.
One day, it'll wake up
and take over the world.
That's great for the
movies, but it's fiction.
The systems we have today
are nowhere near capable
of some of the simplest
things humans can do.
And humans are complex
beyond our own understanding.
One of the most powerful
methods of AI programming
is based on how we think the brain works,
but we don't really know.
But even imitating how
we guess the brain works
has resulted in systems
that are far more powerful
than any other programming
we've had before.
But they are only far more capable
at very specific functions.
They do not reason, they don't grow wise,
they do not even have common sense.
Can they do simultaneous
translation? Sure.
Can they win at Jeopardy
and chess and go? Yes.
But none of them can
do all of these things.
So when you use AI to build a model
to predict an outcome,
or decide on an email subject line,
that is functional AI,
and it is an awesome tool.
But it's only a tool, not a handyman.
It's a saw, not a carpenter.
It's a paintbrush, not a painter.
It can only do the specific task
that it was built to do,
but it does it really well, really fast,
and it gets better over time.
The kind of tasks that we're talking
about are language, vision, robotics.
These are AI's sweet spots.
Natural language processing
has gotten much better lately.
You can talk into your phone
and it will translate
your voice into text.
A conversation bot can imitate speech
so we can converse with smart speakers.
Computer vision lets you ask your computer
for the photos that you've taken of dogs
or people who are at the beach
or on my summer vacation.
Computer vision can recognize
your logo on social media,
even at an odd angle.
Computer vision is getting good enough
that we will be getting self-driving cars.
And then there's machine learning.
This is the heart of AI for marketing.
Machine learning is the tool
that can help you improve
prospect targeting,
respond to inquiries faster,
determine the next best
action for lead nurturing,
qualify leads for the sales team.
The list goes on.
Machines are getting better and better
at identifying patterns
and predicting outcomes,
as long as you have a
very clear task for it.
So imagine that you've just
hired a new marketing intern.
What sort of tasks would you give somebody
who is smart, learns quick,
but doesn't really have
a lot of experience?
What tasks would you give a fresh recruit?
Make that list, it's the starting point
to making artificial
intelligence work for you.