- Artificial intelligence
is tremendously useful
for marketing, and I'm
glad you're interested.
Rest assured that AI is not
going to take over the world
and enslave mankind, it's
not going to take your job.
That's just not going to happen.
It is going to take
over some of your tasks
so that you can do your job
better, faster, and cheaper.
But there's some things
that you need to be aware of
when you want to use AI.
I can help you avoid
some of the speed bumps
and the potholes in just
a couple of minutes.
Start by remembering what
economist Leo Cherne said.
"Computers are incredibly fast,
fast, accurate, and stupid,
"while humans are slow,
error-prone, and brilliant.
"The marriage of the two is
a force beyond calculation."
Yes, even artificial intelligence is dumb.
It can only do what you tell it
and it does not know if
the answer is reasonable.
It's really good at telling good from bad,
but it hasn't got a clue
about right from wrong.
If you tell the machine that
you want more email opens,
the algorithm might figure out
that sending everybody 1,000
emails gets more of them open.
That could be true, but it's
not helpful, it's not useful.
So you have to be very
clear about your goals
with artificial intelligence.
What specifically do you
want it to do for you?
Next, you've got to give the
machine the best data you can.
Good data is clean and
reliable and abundant
and of the proper variety.
You may have a million customers,
but it's the variety of what you know
about those customers that matters.
Name and address won't tell you very much,
but name, address, time
of day they contact you,
and what they look at on your website
starts to get predictive of
what and when they might buy.
Too little information is not helpful.
The machine will just be
highly confident, but wrong.
Too many data types,
and the machine won't be confident at all,
it's just all noise.
It's up to you to find the
right assortment of data
for the machine to answer
your questions well.
The other troubling thing about
data is that it is biased.
A group of data scientists at Amazon
asked the machine to
filter out the resumes
of people who were not likely
to be successful Amazon employees.
Success was I find based
on a lot of factors,
including the number of promotions,
the number of direct reports,
glowing reviews, years
of service, the usual.
But the results were a pile of
resumes of only white males.
The bias built into the data
uncovered their diversity problems.
So Amazon had to throw out that algorithm
to guard against future bias.
Finally, this is a tool,
and all tools can be used for good or ill.
Should we be afraid of AI?
Not at all.
Should we be we afraid of bad actors
using AI to defraud people,
mess with our election process,
turn a blind eye to discrimination?
Yes, we should.
So it's on you to make sure
that your projects are
well-defined, your data is diverse,
and that you are making sure
the machine doesn't do the
wrong thing by accident
or fall into the wrong hands.
Keep those things top of mind
and you can use AI to become
more valuable to your company
and make your company more successful.