- Hollywood loves to
make movies about robots
that miraculously develop
integrated cognition.
Wall-E, the robot who learns to love,
Dolores from Westworld who seeks revenge,
or even R2-D2's distinct
loyalty to the rebellion.
But that's just Hollywood magic.
Artificial intelligence can
find a needle in a haystack,
but it can't have a new idea.
AI can discover a new
pattern of correlation,
but it can't tell if that new pattern
of correlation is interesting or useful.
Artificial intelligence
can add two plus two,
but it can't put two and two together.
That ability is your superpower.
Your superpower allows you to
take everything in your mind,
your imagination, your
memory, your knowledge,
your feelings, and apply
it all to a new problem.
That's what we call integrated cognition.
And it really is a super human power.
I want to help you get
ahead and stay ahead with AI
by understanding and
honing your superpower.
First, I want you to have
a strong understanding
of integrated cognition.
Integrated cognition is all about learning
from one area and applying it to another.
Analogies are a really
good example of this.
We use analogies a lot
in human communication
because it allows us to
condense information.
That new restaurant is like
my favorite Mexican place
with great bar and live music.
Or that new Netflix series
is like "Game of Thrones" without dragons.
Or driving a Tesla is like
riding on a magic car,
but until you ask it to drive itself.
We take learning from all areas
and apply it to every other.
Your worldview has been
crafted over a whole lifetime
of learning and experience.
All the books you've read,
the movies you've seen,
the meetings you've been
in, all blend together
in this wondrous
interpretation of the world
that is yours and yours alone.
When you bring all of that to the table,
you are adding a very unique
ingredient to the conversation.
So practice open-mindedness,
be curious to hear what others think,
explore new avenues for learning
and be open to new experiences and ideas.
You never know when that
intel might come in handy.
Another element of integrated
cognition is collaboration.
When you put your unique perspective
and your integrated cognition
into a room with a dozen others
who have all had a completely
different worldview
built on their own unique lives,
that's when the sparks fly,
that's collaboration at its best.
Your ability to work with
others and enhance their ideas
cannot be duplicated by a machine.
Your ability to use empathy,
to put yourself in another person's shoes,
your capacity to accept new ideas
and allow yourself to question
your fundamental beliefs,
even for just a moment, will
make you an invaluable player
in a world filled with artificial
intelligence applications.
So ask people to challenge your ideas.
Listen, try and see things
from a different point of view.
That's a uniquely human skill,
but you need to practice.
When you're putting together a team
to brainstorm or solve a problem,
make sure you have as diverse a group
of people in the room as you can.
Race, gender, age, nationality.
The more variety of
worldviews in the room,
the richer the conversation,
the more comprehensive
and sophisticated the discussion,
and the more valuable the outcome.
I want you to find opportunities
to hone your human superpowers.
Next time you have a new team member,
be curious to get to know them.
When you make a presentation,
ask people to challenge your ideas.
When you're troubleshooting,
try to see things from a different angle
or a whole different point of view.
You'll go far, once you
understand that having new ideas
and seeing things from
a different perspective
beats the heck out of finding
that needle in a haystack every time.