- In 1993, Don Peppers and
Martha Rogers wrote a book
called "The One to One Future".
They only mention the internet in passing,
because it was only 1993,
but they laid out the
concept of using computers
to communicate with individuals at scale.
The concept was to treat each
person as a unique individual
even though you're dealing with thousands
of people at the same time.
The idea is straightforward.
When somebody shows up on your website,
you show them whatever pictures
and text might be the
most useful or persuasive
in order to create a fabulous
personalized customer experience.
Everybody wants to be
treated as an individual.
recognized and remembered
and have their specific
needs kept in mind.
It's why we like going back
to the same restaurant.
"Would you like the usual madam?"
"Why yes, I would, thank you."
I want to show you how machine learning
can help your company get
better at personalization.
You'll be able to convert
more prospects into customers,
make your customers happier,
make your company more profitable.
The non-AI version starts
with you sitting in a room
with the smartest people in your company
and coming up with complex rules
for what to show which people.
If your customer lives
in a southern state,
has purchased this pair of running shoes,
and has recently visited a
competitive running shoe website,
then you might want to show
them this particular content
on the landing page, because you figure
they're looking for a new pair of shoes,
and you can guess which
ones they'll like the best.
Or if your customer also purchased
this other pair of shoes,
and they click on customer support,
then you want to take them to the FAQ,
frequently asked questions page,
about that shoe failing in
the southern summer heat,
because you can guess why they showed up.
You can spend the rest
of your career coming up
with scenarios like this.
You could come up with
elaborate flowcharts
about if they do this, then we think that.
Some of it is professional experience
garnered over time, and the
rest is just conjecture.
But I want you to let that old way go.
I want you to let machine
learning watch people
coming to your website
and track as many traits
and behaviors as it can,
and let it try new things.
That's how machine learning works.
It's how it learns.
It tries things.
And when something works, it
tries them again and again,
and it improves, it learns.
Over time, when somebody
comes to your website,
the algorithm will have
the best possible content
to show them provided you've given
the algorithm enough to work with.
Start by coming up with
a variety of personas
and scenarios for which you
create a variety of content.
Then you let the machine
learning algorithm mix
and match your text and pictures
to show a wide variety of visitors.
In time, you'll see that it
can make real-time decisions
to improve the customer experience
and make you look like the
brilliant marketing professional
you have become.