- A toddler can tell the
difference between a cat and a dog
with only a few examples.
Now what if that child
could find and count
all the people on social media
who are wearing your sunglasses
or holding your energy drink
or had your car in the background?
See how that might be
useful for marketing.
Artificial intelligence and
cameras give us computer vision.
A whole new way of interacting
with prospects and customers,
and understanding this technology,
its limitations and possibilities,
will give you a leg up on the competition.
Like most AI, computer
vision isn't perfect.
It's great at recognizing things,
but don't for a minute think,
that it understands what it sees.
Can it tell a cat from a dog?
Most of the time.
But small things can throw it off
because the computer is not
making sense of the world,
it's looking at pixels
and deciding that these
shapes and these shades
have a higher probability of being a cat.
If the cat is looking the wrong way,
has its ears down, is curled up asleep,
the computer's confused.
That's the catch.
You have to show the computer
tens of thousands of pictures
that you have labeled cats
before it can do its thing.
This is called supervised learning.
You know those Captcha prove
you're not a robot logins,
that's you labeling the
data for computer vision.
You are teaching the computer
how to recognize the street sign,
the crosswalk, the traffic light.
Don't you think self-driving
cars would want to know?
The technology can get
pretty sophisticated,
even giving us facial recognition
and augmented reality.
The computer can recognize
that your face is a face
and that it's your face.
You can unlock your phone
just by looking at it.
The computer can also identify
the features of your face
and the result is all those
silly Snapchat filters.
You've probably played
with Zoom backgrounds.
Yup, computer vision.
So what are the
possibilities for marketing?
Depending on your product or service,
computer vision can open up
new avenues for connecting you
with your customers and prospects.
You might let people
view your virtual product
in their actual home.
Maybe you let people try
on virtual hairstyles
or lipstick colors or
1,000 different outfits,
or overlay additional
information on your products
when people view them through
their phones' camera augmented reality,
or you could automatically
recognize your loyal customers
when they walk in the
door, facial recognition.
What used to just be science fiction
is now a tool for the
marketing department.
How do you interact with your customers?
Brainstorm with your team.
Come up with all the ways
computer vision might be useful
and figure out which
ones are worth testing.
Then when some Chief something
or other officer asks
if the marketing department is using AI,
you can assure them that
you're on top of it.