- Wouldn't machine learning be terrific
if it could actually learn,
like actually learn things
about where to spend
your advertising dollars
or which messages are best
for which type of prospect,
or which offers are the most compelling?
It only takes a few minutes to learn
what reinforcement
learning can do for you,
and that will make you more
valuable to your company
and give your company a decisive
edge over your competitors.
Reinforcement learning is where
you give the computer a task
and a goal and let it
learn from the results
of its own actions.
For example, the task:
improve email subject lines,
the goal: get more people
to open our emails,
the action: test a variety
of email subject lines
to find the most effective.
The algorithm starts with
your example subject lines
and starts sending out emails.
It keeps track of which
get opened looks at
what the successful subject
lines have in common,
and then generates more subject lines
that are like the winners.
Sounds like something you could use?
I want to help you find more ways
to incorporate reinforcement learning
to make your marketing better.
Let's say you want to automate
product recommendations.
If your goal is to get
people to put more items
in their shopping cart, you
can write a simple program
to pop up three product suggestions.
When the customer hits
the shopping cart button,
you can brainstorm some really good ideas,
like offering a camera case
and extra memory to somebody
who just bought a camera.
And you can simply show the classic people
who bought this also bought that,
but this doesn't scale well
when you have thousands of products.
That's where reinforcement
learning comes in.
Instead, the algorithm tries a few things
and starts to see patterns.
It may make no sense that people
who buy coffee cups will
also want to put potholders
into their cart, but if it's
true and the algorithm spots it
and offers potholders,
then your sales go up.
Now be careful here
because reinforcement learning looks a lot
like a child learning to walk.
It'll take a step and fall down,
and then it'll take two
steps and fall down,
then it'll take four steps and
run right out into traffic.
You know the classic
entrepreneurial agile command
to fail fast?
Well, that's what reinforcement
learning actually does.
Unless you set some guide rails
at the start, it'll try
things almost at random
and make horrible mistakes,
but as soon as it randomly
succeeds, it has a toehold
and then it does better
and better and better.
What tasks are you currently
farming out to interns?
What would you do better or at all
if you had a room full of
interns who could crank
through lots of data, really fast?
What's on your to-do list
that is actually important,
but you find so overwhelming
you never get around to it.
Congratulations, you just
created a list of things
that you can turn over
to reinforcement learning, well done.