- How would you like to be an AI-powered
marketing professional?
No, I'm not talking about
turning you into a cyborg.
I'm talking about giving you the skills
to harness the power of
artificial intelligence
for yourself, personally,
so you can be the one to lead the pack.
You'll have a huge advantage
over others in your company
or in the pool of candidates
vying for that new job.
The first step to becoming
an AI-savvy marketer
is blindingly straightforward.
Learn about the SQL data
management programming language.
I don't mean that you
need to learn to code SQL
or become a programmer.
I mean that you need to understand
what it is and how it works.
Even just spending an hour
reading the Wikipedia article
about SQL will give you a serious boost.
Next,
learn the most popular
marketing automation tools
and their AI components.
IBM has Watson Marketing Insights,
Salesforce has Einstein,
Adobe has Sensei.
These are AI tools built
into each marketing platform.
You don't need to learn them all,
but you should learn one of them.
The one your company uses,
or the one that you can get
your hands on the easiest.
That'll help you learn any of the others
when you come across them.
It's like driving,
when you apply to be a delivery person.
They want to know if you can drive.
Whether you learned in a Ford F-150
or a Chevy Silverado doesn't matter,
so long as you know your
way around a pick-up.
Finally, and this is the sweet spot.
Augment yourself with AI tools.
Train your own bots to
enhance the way you work.
You use spell check, right?
You've been adding unique
words to your dictionary.
This isn't AI,
but it is personalized spell check
and it's a start.
When you write formulas
in Excel spreadsheets,
you are programming it
to think like you do.
Maybe you've even written
some Excel macros.
you are building a library
of cognitive shortcuts.
Now,
let's add some AI power to your toolkit.
What about an AI meeting scheduler?
There are tools that act
like a personal assistant
to arrange a meeting.
Doodle poll?
Oh, that's so last decade.
This AI version looks at your calendar,
knows which day has a big
enough gap in meetings
to make it to your favorite
restaurant and back.
And then it negotiates over email
with the people you're meeting
to set the appointment,
and it updates your calendar.
There are now auto-complete systems
that use machine learning
to suggest ways to finish
sentences you start.
Trainable to your writing style.
You teach it how you write,
and then you can write a lot faster.
You train your bots to do
just about anything your way.
Train them to book travel the way you like
or manage your expense
reporting the way you want.
Or review contracts for problems
you know, might be there.
So here's what I want you to do.
Make a list of all the
repetitive tasks that you do
that you could train an intern to do.
That new intern is AI.
Do your research.
Look around for which
AI systems specialize
in what you're looking for.
As they say, there's an app for that.
Pick one or two to
familiarize yourself with,
and start training your bots.
When you've become a full-fledged
AI powered professional,
list the team of AI agents
that you have adopted
and trained on your resume
or LinkedIn profile.
That shows you are a standout.
And the best marketing
professional for the job.