- It's called big data
because it is more data
than a human can wrangle,
has more attributes
than a human can manage,
and more permutations than
the human mind can comprehend.
But machine learning is so powerful,
because it is so good at
dimensionality and cardinality.
Let me break it down
so you will know when machine
learning would be useful,
what kinds of problems
it's good at solving,
and you'll be able to tell
when some so-called data scientist
is trying to pull the wool over your eyes.
You've got a lot of data.
Let's say you have a
hundred thousand customers
or even a million.
That's great.
You can't keep a million
customers in your head,
but an Excel spreadsheet
can manage that just fine.
So let's make it harder.
Let's say you know a thousand
things about a million people,
that's a thousand columns
of things that you know
in a database with a
million rows of customers.
If you want to know how many customers
are in a given zip code,
how many of those are
subscribed to your email list
and have purchased from you
in the past three months,
spreadsheet can still handle that.
But if you wanted to know
what other patterns
are present in the data
without you having to come
up with a specific question,
you could ask an infinite
number of interns
to look at the data and cross-reference it
six ways to Sunday for months
and they might not come up
with something interesting.
But machine learning can
easily handle tens of thousands
of columns about millions of customers.
That's dimensionality.
Each column holds a thing that
you know about each customer,
that's a dimension.
And you get to tens of thousands
of things when you add in
behavioral data like social media activity
and website visits and past
purchase and what they said
when they call the call center and so on.
Lots of dimensions about each person.
Then comes cardinality,
which is a fancy word for the
number of possible entries
in each dimension.
Take age for example,
the number of possible
entries in the age field
is somewhere between zero
and 122, so far as we know.
Do they live in California?
Ah, only two possible
answers there, yes or no,
really low cardinality.
But what's their phone number?
If half the people on the
planet have their own phone,
there are 4 billion possibilities
for that one field alone,
that one dimension.
Think about your spreadsheet
as having lots and lots of rows
and lots and lots of columns.
The rows are the objects of the people,
the columns are the
dimensions or the attributes
of what you know about them.
And cardinality is all about
how many possible options
there are in a given dimension.
With data that's that rich and that deep,
you need something seriously
powerful to deal with it.
And that's where machine learning shines.
So I want you to get to
know your company's data.
Where is your company now
regarding dimensionality
and cardinality?
What additional data could you add
that will open up more doors?
How can you better understand and expand
your data's dimensionality
and cardinality?
Keep this in mind
when it's time to talk about
leveraging marketing data
and you'll be better equipped
to suggest artificial intelligence
uses in your own company.
Identify when machine
learning might be overkill
and navigate the conversation
with the data science team.