- Arthur C. Clarke famously said,
"Any sufficiently advanced technology
"is indistinguishable from magic."
This couldn't be more true
for artificial intelligence.
AI is so advanced that people
dedicate entire careers
to understanding it.
Now, I know what you might be thinking.
How do you put machine
learning to work in marketing
if you can't even converse
with a career data scientist?
I want to help you understand
what machine learning is in general,
how it is different from
everything that came before it
and how different flavors
of machine learning
can solve different kinds of problems
so you can start exploring
where and when to use it.
Machine learning is a
new type of programming,
a way of telling the computer
what you want it to do.
We started with COBOL and FORTRAN and C,
strict instructions to
be executed exactly.
Next comes mathematical models,
simple ones like your budget
in an Excel spreadsheet.
Change the values to play what if games,
even change the formulas,
which are just short programs
linked from cell to cell.
Beyond that comes predictive analytics.
These are handcrafted statistical models
built with lots of
assumptions and tweaking
to make a model reflect
the real world well enough
to make predictions.
Machine learning is software
that looks at a pile of data
and builds a model based on the data.
It looks for patterns and derives rules
about the data from the data
and uses that to answer
questions or make predictions.
The learning in machine
learning comes from the fact
that it can change its mind.
When new data shows up, it reassesses,
looks for new patterns
and updates its own
mathematical model of the world.
Now, there are three broad
types of machine learning.
The first is supervised learning.
This is where you know the answer,
give the machine lots and lots of examples
and ask it questions like,
is this a photo of a dog or a cat?
Who out there looks like my best customer?
Which of my customers are
best suited for upselling?
Next is unsupervised learning.
This is where you ask the
machine to tell you something
that you didn't know.
Find a pattern.
Show me a correlation I wouldn't
have thought to look for.
And finally, there's
reinforcement learning.
This is a whole different animal.
You give the machine a task and a goal
and it makes changes
that improve the outcome.
You want more email opens?
The machine can crank out
a bunch of subject lines,
see which ones get opened,
then creates and tests subject lines
that are more like the
ones that got opened.
It learns from its own actions.
Do you see the power here?
We can teach the machine
to score prospects
based on our customer data
or determine what messaging
would be the best next action
or qualify leads for the sales team
or predict which prospects
are the most likely
to be high lifetime value customers.
Now it can seem pretty daunting
to get started using machine learning,
but actually it's not that difficult.
Here's what I want you to do.
Make a list of the tasks
that software like this
might do for your company,
what problems it could solve,
what barriers it could remove,
what tasks it might be able to improve.
You then prioritize that list
and start that conversation
with your data scientists,
your consulting agencies,
and your technology vendors.
Once you have an idea of the
problems you'd like to solve,
you'll be able to take advantage
of this magical software
before you know it.