- The robots are coming
to change marketing,
and you can work with them
and become even more successful,
or get crushed under their metal feet.
Today artificial intelligence is all hype
and little understanding.
If you're a marketing professional,
you've heard all the buzz,
but you probably don't
know what to believe.
In this course, I'm going to bring you
from zero to hero in your understanding
of how AI and machine learning
can be put to use by you in marketing.
I'm Jim Sterne.
I'm a consultant and co-founder
of the Digital Analytics Association
and author of "Artificial
Intelligence for Marketing."
In this course, I'm going
to help you understand
what AI is, how machine
learning is a powerful tool,
and how you can integrate it
into your marketing initiatives,
no matter how big or tech-savvy
your company is at the moment.
So let's take this first step
into this exciting new world.
Come start the journey with me.