- Self-driving cars and robots
are always lumped into
artificial intelligence,
even though they are not.
It's important to understand
why they aren't really AI.
Give me a minute, and I'll
help you understand AI
and show you how
self-driving cars and robots
actually will be part of marketing.
Google Maps can tell
you how long it'll take
to get where you're going.
That is some serious heavy lifting,
and is artificial intelligence.
They use machine learning
to constantly improve.
Talking to Siri or Alexa,
absolutely learning on the job.
But most robots are just
machines executing instructions.
Remember that remarkable video of Atlas
from Boston dynamics where
it does that back flip?
Amazing, but here's the thing.
It didn't learn how to do a back flip.
Its programmers learn how
to tweak the instructions
so Atlas could amaze us.
It took 50 tries.
Self-driving cars use a
wide range of technologies
to do what they do,
and there is a great
deal of machine learning
involved in their initial training.
But if each car were
left to learn on its own,
the product liability lawyers
would have a field day.
So what can these almost
artificial intelligence things
do for your marketing?
If you run a service-only
or online-only business,
robots aren't very helpful.
But if your business is in person,
there are a variety of ways
they might be useful or entertaining.
One Japanese hotel offers check-in
with a pretty robot attendant
or a dinosaur robot.
Fun!
A porter robot takes your
luggage to your room,
where you unlock the door with your face.
Useful!
No, robots can't make the bed
or handle the wide variety
of concierge questions yet.
But it's a start.
And yes, Lowe's tried
customer service robots
in their home improvement stores,
and then went back to the drawing board.
But these are all at the very start.
If you run a store,
start daydreaming now
(icons pop)
about how a robot might help
deliver additional clothes
to try on in the changing room,
or restock the shelves on the main floor,
or act as a follow me
around shopping cart.
These ideas are all doable.
It's just a question of choosing
which ones will be the most useful
and which people will like the most.
Self-driving cars offer a
whole new promotional platform
that deserves your attention.
If people are not driving,
they are sleeping,
working, watching entertainment,
and in a perfect position for advertising.
Maybe you create a branded app
for meditation or in-car learning.
You could offer
location-specific messaging
and even coordinate those messages
with electronic billboards.
Or, "Hey Ashley, you have 45 minutes
before your next appointment.
Auto Realty would like to take you
on a guided tour of homes for sale.
Say yes and they'll give you
a free inspection valuation
of your current home."
Or, "Hey, Matthew, Kraft
would like to show you
a simple recipe for macaroni and cheese
that your kids will love.
Say okay, and they'll
deliver the ingredients
to your door and give you a 20% coupon."
Or, "Hey Michael, there's
a Starbucks coming up.
Say yes, and you can have
your pumpkin spice chai latte
handed to you in two minutes."
Yes, this stuff is off in the future.
But now is the time to
start brainstorming.
Because things are moving fast.
Position yourself to be
ready and at the forefront.
Your brand could get a huge PR bump
by being the first to try something.
What might you offer
that could make a splash?
You may not think your brand has anything
to do with self-driving
cars or robots yet,
but now is the time to challenge yourself.
It's not a matter of if, but when.