- And there you have it.
You have reached the end of the course.
I want to thank you very
much for joining me.
I am excited that you are
now well enough informed
to determine what kind of
artificial intelligence projects
will help your customers,
work in your company,
and provide the most
return on your investment
of time and energy.
You are also prepared to choose
what role you want to play
in implementing artificial intelligence.
There are a lot of options.
And you get to pick whichever
fit your temperament the best.
I would like you to extend your education
in whatever way makes sense for you.
Start by taking a look at my book,
"Artificial Intelligence for Marketing:
Practical Applications."
Check out other online
education opportunities
and community organizations
like your university of choice
or the Marketing Artificial
Intelligence Institute,
which is marketingaiinstitute.com.
And if you really want to
know more about data science
and dig deeply into machine learning,
I strongly recommend
"This Week in Machine
Learning and AI TWIML."
It's a podcast, TWIMLAI.com.
It gets very deep very quickly,
but it's a great way to learn
the language of data science
but listening to how data scientists
talk to other data scientists.
It's eye-opening.
I don't understand, hmm, maybe 70% of it.
But it's really interesting to listen to.
And now, I want you to do me a favor.
Please get in touch with me directly
and tell me about your progress
in adopting artificial intelligence
and machine learning for marketing.
We're at the very beginning of
this new exciting technology.
And sharing your experience with me
will allow me to help others.
So please email me at
jsterne@targeting.com
or find me on Twitter @JimSterne
because now it's my
turn to learn from you.