- If you're doing any online advertising,
you might already be
using machine learning
and just not know it.
Programmatic advertising is the norm today
because the enormous
volume of ads on Google
and Facebook and Twitter and all the rest.
Once you understand how machine
learning alters the process,
you can make better use of
programmatic advertising
and get better results for your ads.
In the good old days,
you'd check off the traits of the audience
you were targeting,
age, gender, location, education,
and the publishers
computer would show your ad
to the person with those traits.
Programmatic means that the
system does the matching,
which is huge because the average person
sees something like 5,000 ads everyday.
Multiply that by half the
population on the planet,
and it's a lot of ads to serve.
It's more efficient for
you, the advertiser,
to go to an intermediary, an ad exchange,
and let them figure out
where to place your ad
based on your desired audience traits.
You get to choose how much
you're willing to pay per ad,
bidding against others,
and how much you're
willing to spend per day,
budget control,
and the computers work out the details.
With machine learning,
you do not choose the audience traits.
You choose the desired outcome.
You might want your ad to
generate more click throughs
to measure response and awareness
or more page views on your site
because you sell advertising
or more people signing up for
your newsletter or more sales.
You ask for the outcome,
then you let the machine
learning algorithm figure out
how to make that happen.
The algorithm will try
a variety of your ads
to see which ones work
on which types of people.
Now, the interesting part
is that types of people are not logical.
Women between 18 and 34 in suburbs,
whom you think might like your minivan,
instead, there are
people who have something
statistically in common with those
who performed the desired outcome.
It's not logical, it's mathematical.
It might not make sense that the people
who have this type of computer
and that kind of browser
and read articles about ponies
before eight o'clock in the morning
are the most likely to buy a minivan.
But if they are, the algorithm makes note
and finds others like them
and shows them your ad.
Because this is artificial intelligence,
that combination of traits and behaviors
is not written in stone,
instead, it is continuously
updated profiles
of micro segments of your target audience,
and there might be hundreds
or thousands of micro segments
being monitored and
advertised to at any time.
So instead of wasting time trying to guess
what kind of person might respond,
start thinking about the
different kinds of messages
that might resonate with
different kinds of people,
create a variety of ads
for the machine to show the whole world
and let the algorithm sort out
where you should spend your money.
That's how you take
advantage of machine learning
and programmatic advertising.