- What do you say
when a toddler reaches for
something on the ground?
"Don't touch that, you
never know where it's been."
That's how you should
feel about your data.
Even in the most straightforward
charts and graphs,
if you don't know where
your data came from,
how it was harvested,
how it was processed,
you don't want to make
important business decisions
based on that.
Garbage in, garbage out
has always been the case with computers,
but now we're using machine
learning to analyze data.
It's even more important
that you know the lineage of your data.
How do you keep from getting
blindsided by bad data?
By taking responsibility for it.
Imagine you run a soup factory.
20 to 30 ingredients come
in through the shipping dock
and thousands of cans of
chicken soup go out the back.
Now, if your soup makes people sick,
you have to figure out which
ingredient caused the problem.
Was it the water, the salt,
the chicken, the veggies?
Each one of those is handled
in such a different way
that you need people
with special knowledge
to manage the acquisition, handling,
and cooking of each one.
Same thing with data.
Data is collected, formatted, cleaned,
moved into a database
where it can be reformatted
so it can be combined with other data
and then poured into a
huge data storage bin
where the machine learning
algorithm can access it.
That's a lot of steps where
a lot of things can go wrong.
You won't know there's a problem
until your soup starts making people sick.
You won't know the data is
corrupted until it's too late.
For instance, did the computer
recommend sending coupons
for contact lenses to people
who read braille books?
Did the algorithm advise
promoting your elder care products
to college students?
Did the model predict
that sales of ice cream
will triple in the winter?
You'll need a data steward
for each data stream.
So you have somebody with knowledge
to track down why the output
from the algorithm doesn't
pass the smell test.
We have so much data now.
So many different kinds of data
that you need to start with an inventory
of what data you have
about your customers.
And what you can find
out about your prospects.
You have, or can get
information about who they are,
their identity, what they've done,
their history, what they
like, their preferences,
what they own, their possessions,
what they do, their activities
and how they feel,
their moods and beliefs.
All of that is available.
When you put all that together,
you can generate some
supremely powerful insights,
but if you don't have a data steward
to monitor each data stream,
you are flying blind.
You need to be able to trust your data
to the point where you'd be willing
to make serious business decisions,
stake your reputation, and
bet your job on the output.
The very first step is
to make that inventory
of what data you rely on to
run your part of the business.
Next, go make friends
with every individual
who collects and manages
each one of those datasets.
Buy them lunch, ask them
about their process.
Find out how confident they
are in the technology they use.
You are now on the path to data literacy.
Soon you'll be able to see the big picture
and you'll know whom to turn to
when bad data causes the algorithm
to recommend that you
sell all of your products
for 3 cents with free shipping.